A Guide to the Papers of J. Harry Michael, 1892-1994
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of J. Harry Michael, 1892-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10071-h
This collection consists of ca. 3175 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library from Harry Michael, Jr. of Charlottesville, Va. on October 19, 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
J. Harry Michael, Jr. was a Virginia State Senator, Judge, and United States District Court for the Western District of Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This collection includes J. Harry Michael, Jr.'s personal correspondence, 1941-1945, from World War II, particularly letters written by him from the Naval Training School at Harvard. The collection also consists of letters to him from friends and family, including two from Dean Ivey Lewis on the University of Virginia during the war.
In addition, the collection contains a personal data questionnaire and accompanying drafts and research submitted by Michael as a candidate for the U.S. District Judge for the Western District of Virginia. There are letters of congratulations on his appointment and material from a seminar for newly appointed district judges sponsored by the Federal Judicial Center, including copies of lectures.
The collection also contains desk calendars of appointments, conferences and court dates, pocket calendars, and invitations.
Arrangement
These items are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Judicial Papers, 1974-1994, 12 items
  These items are arranged alphabetically.
  - Calendar: Appointments and Scheduled Events, 1987-1989, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Calendar: Appointments and Scheduled Events, 1990- June 1992, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Calendar: Appointments and Scheduled Events, 1992- July 1994, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Calendar: Appointment Books, 1987-1994 (Box 4)
  - Invitations, 1986-1989, 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Judgeship- Congratulations: A-Z, 1980, 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Judgeship- Federal Judicial Center- Seminar for Newly Appointed District Judges, June 1980, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Judgeship- Federal Judicial Center- Seminar for Newly Appoionted District Judges, June 1980, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Judgeship- Senate Judiciary Committee- Personal Data Questionnaire, 1979, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Judgeship- Senate Judiciary Committee- Personal Data Questionnaire, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Judgeship- Senate Judiciary Committee- Personal Data Questionnaire- Preparation Materials, 1974-1980, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Judgeship- Senate Judiciary Committee- Personal Data Questionnaire- Completed Copies, 1980, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Personal Papers 1892-1980, 17 items
  - J. Harry Michael to Jean Moir, 1943, 14 folders (Box 8)
  - J. Harry Michael to Jean Moir, 1944, 11 folders (Box 9)
  - J. Harry Michael to Jean Moir, 1945 (Box 9)
  - Letters to J. Harry Michael, 1941-1945 (Box 10)
  - Birchall, Margaretta M. to J. Harry Michael, 1944-1945 (Box 10)
  - Michael, D. Hester to J. Harry Michael, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Michael, Mattie J., to J. Harry Michael, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Michael, Ruby (Shelton) to J. Harry Michael, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Michael, Warren T. to J. Harry Michael, 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Moir, Jean to J. Harry Michael, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Musselman, Robert M. to J. Harry Michael, 1944 (Box 10)
  - Noland, Thomas B. to J. Harry Michael, 1944 (Box 10)
  - Norton, Jane to J. Harry Michael, 1942-1944 (Box 10)
  - University of Virginia to J. Harry Michael, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Financial and Legal Papers of J. Harry Michael and Family, 1892-1945 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of J. Harry Michael and Family 1938-1980 (Box 10)
  - Certification of Ruby (Shelton) Michael as a Real Estate Broker for the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1949, 2 copies (Oversize p-24)